Hyderabad, India +91 8555845324 srikarpanuganti08@gmail.com

# Srikar Panuganti Web Developer

Portfolio: <a href="mailto:srikar-io.vercel.app">srikar-io.vercel.app</a> <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/srikarpanuganti">linkedin.com/in/srikarpanuganti</a> <a href="mailto:github.com/srikar8968">github.com/srikar8968</a>

Web Developer with more than 2+ years of experience and seeking a proven process in the position of a developer to further enhance organizational worth owing to my knowledge in development and dedicated to further developing career skills at professional level to meet company targets and culture.

# **Work Experience**

## Web Developer

## **Stratistics Market Research Consulting**

Jan 2020 - Present

- Revamped security layers, optimizations, testing and maintenance with improved performance score of 97+ from 63 and with a minimized downtime of 18%
- Built seamless automatic managing procedures with trending JavaScript technologies (React.js, Vue.js), and MVC Architectures(Laravel, CodeIgniter)
- Implemented SPA for site administrations and multi-user role using api token management for CMS software with the help of React.js
- Worked as a sole developer and so in other 4 partnering sites, built responsive design mockups for landing pages and constantly fixing user reported defects time to time
- Preparation of test cases and test review ensured high traffic rates, page clicks, and user experience by 52%

## **Web Developer**

## **Credence Apps and Reports**

May 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and user experience, resulting in 94+ performance score
- Built CMS with automatic web functionalities using MVC Architecture(CodeIgniter)
- Implemented site administration and user role management with seamless leads management, resulted increase in user leads by 70%
- Maintaining site performance, logs and fixing bugs resulted in constant performance\traffic numbers
- Responsible for overseeing overall quality procedures for full life cycle of software development with 100% on-time delivery

# **Technologies and Languages**

• Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript(ES5, ES6), PHP, MySQL, C++

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Laravel, Codelgniter, Tailwind CSS
 Tools: Visual Studio Code, Git, Dream-weaver, FileZilla, Lighthouse

## **Education**

• **Diploma in Embedded Systems,** Govt. Institute of Electronics.

May 2016 - April 2019

GPA: 8.8 | C++, Embedded C, Assembly Programming, Verilog HDL

## **Projects**

• <u>srikar.io</u> Personal Portfolio and Blog - (Next.js, TypeScript, mdx, gsap)

• WebWynk Music app - (React.js, Spotify API, TailwindCss, Auth)

<u>Seiko Dev</u> Experimental Developer's Community - (Next.js, styled-components, gsap)

• <u>CovidTracker</u> Detailed global Covid analysis - (API, JavaScript, Bootstrap)

## **Certifications**

• Quark Summer Technical Projects (QSTP) BITS Pilani - Certificate of Excellence

May 2021 - June 2021

Infasta Soft Solutions - Certificate of Excellence

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

#### **Interests**

Designing | Coding | Reading Articles | Football | Art | Travel